arcgis.com 2014-06-29

# Legal Information | Privacy Statement ArcGIS Online

## ArcGIS Online

**Effective Date: June 28, 2013**

**Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (“Esri”) values the privacy of those who use our online SAAS based service, ArcGIS Online.** We think it is important for you to understand when and why we collect personally identifiable information and how we may use it. This Privacy Policy describes Esri data collection and use policies when you provide it to us via ArcGIS Online. The use of information collected through ArcGIS Online shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has Esri. Please read the entire Privacy Policy before providing any personally identifiable information to Esri. 

Esri has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the ArcGIS Online service.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [info@esri.com](mailto:info@esri.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here.](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint)

Esri complies with the U.S. – E.U. and U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  Esri has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Esri’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. 

**Service Provider Collection and Use**

Esri collects personally identifiable information, such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, user name and password only if our Clients enter/upload this information voluntarily onto ArcGIS Online.  Esri collects information from its Clients, but has no direct relationship with the Client's customers whose personally identifiable information Esri processes on ArcGIS Online.

The voluntary information Esri collects is used to complete transactions; sign up for a trial account; ensure appropriate legal use of Esri services; provide notification to Clients about updates to Esri's and our affiliates' software, data, and services; respond to customer service requests and help provide technical support to our Clients. Esri may also use personally identifiable information to send marketing materials, User Conference information, and newsletters to our Clients. 

**Choice**

Esri collects information from our Clients.If you are a customer of one of Esri's Clients, and would no longer like to be contacted by Esri or by one of our Clients that use our services, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. If you are a Client and would like to update your account please contact us at [info@esri.com](mailto:info@esri.com). 

**Access to Data Controlled by our Clients**

An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his or her query to Esri’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Esri to remove personally identifiable information from Esri computer systems, we  will respond to the Client's request within thirty (30) business days. 

**Data Retention**

Esri may retain personally identifiable information that Esri processes on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Esri may retain and use this personally identifiable information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Security**

The security of your personally identifiable information and our Clients’ information is important to Esri.  During the login process for ArcGIS Online when sensitive information (such as login credentials) is entered Esri encrypts the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  ArcGIS Online allows Esri Clients to choose an option to encrypt other data which is entered or uploaded to the service but no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.  Therefore, Esri cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact [security@esri.com](mailto:security@esri.com).

**How Esri Shares Your Personally Identifiable Information**  
Esri will only share our Client's or Client's customers personally identifiable information as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

_Legal Disclaimer_

Esri reserves the right to disclose our Client's or Client's customers personally identifiable information as required by law and when Esri believes that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our web site.

_Business Transfer_

In the event Esri goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, our Client's or Client's customers personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred.  Our Client's will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of the  personally identifiable information provided to Esri via ArcGIS Online.

**Material Change**

Esri may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If Esri makes any material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify our Clients by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in the Client’s account) or by means of a notice on ArcGIS Online prior to the change becoming effective. Esri encourages our Clients or Client's customers to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact Esri at [info@esri.com](mailto:info@esri.com) or 380 New York Street Redlands, CA. 92373, and Esri will act promptly to investigate, correct as appropriate, and advise you of the correction. Please identify the issue as a Privacy Policy concern in your communication to Esri.
